ANEESH VEMPATY

1585 Danromas Way, San Jose, CA, 95129

Purdue Computer Science graduate with experience building enterprise tools and consumer products. Experience includes developing payment data tools at Visa and consumer products at Micello. Full-Stack problem solver proficient in developing Java backend services and React web applications.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE:

Visa Inc. - Software Engineering Intern

May 2017 - August 2017

408.802.4214 | avempaty@purdue.edu

Portfolio: https://avempaty.github.io/

Customer Data Management Application - Access Control

- Collaborated with Senior Director to create three access-control roles.
- Implemented access-control layer and roles from scratch using Java Spring Framework for pages.
- Improved authentication security by adding server-side validation for all requests.
- Skills: Java (Spring Framework), JavaScript, Internal APIs, Scrum

Payment Analytics and Monitoring Application - Interval View Page

- Created a brand-new interval page to display and filter over 100k daily transactions.
- Developed API endpoints to query more than 50 payment statuses using Splunk.
- Developed a chart using Grafana to display payment statuses for any interval of time.
- Skills: Golang, Javascript, HTML, Splunk, Grafana, Internal APIs, Scrum

Micello Inc. - Software Engineering Intern

June 2015 - August 2015

Indoor Maps - Mall Enhancements

- Built a maps widget for requesting Uber rides from indoor locations.
- Used Micello indoor maps and Uber API to request rides at the most optimal pickup location.
- Implemented indoor directions to navigate user to their pickup location.
- Skills: PHP, JavaScript, PHP, Uber API

Indoor Maps - Airport Enhancements

- Built a travel planning extension for users to get detailed information about flights.
- Used Micello indoor maps and FlightStats API to show flight detail information for each terminal.
- Used AccuWeather's API to give weather, latitude, and longitude information about each flight.
- Skills: PHP, JavaScript, FlightStats API, AccuWeather API

PERSONAL PROJECTS:

Vibe (Fullstack Engineer) - "Instagram for Sharing Music"

January 2018 - May 2018

- https://mymelody.herokuapp.com/
- Developed Feed page. Profile page, and Create-post modal.
- Created all RESTful HTTP API endpoints for users and posts.
- Used Spotify API to play song snippets and get song information.
- Skills: Node.js, REST, Vue, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, MongoDB, Spotify API

Perspective (Game Developer) - "VR Puzzle Game"

August 2016 - December 2016

- https://perspective-499af.firebaseapp.com
- Built a virtual reality puzzle game using Unity 5 with a team of five engineers.
- Led level design from layout, game mechanics, and interactable objects.
- Designed and developed buttons, keys, and doors for each level.
- Skills: Unity 5, C#, Oculus Platform

Uberlytics (Frontend Engineer) - "Uber Surge Price Visualizer"

May 2016 - September 2016

- Built website application that calls the UberRUSH API to graph surge prices
- Worked with Firebase API to collect data and display them on the website
- Skills: React, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Firebase, Uber API

EDUCATION:

Purdue University, West Lafayette, IN B.S. in Computer Science, GPA: 3.21

May 2018

Coursework: Computer Architecture, Distributed Systems, Algorithms, Data Structures, ML, Testing **Languages:** Java, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, C, C++, C#, R, SQL, Python

Frameworks/Programs: Spring, Unity 5, Splunk, Grafana, MEAN Stack, React, Vue, Firebase, Node.js